Inventory of the Church A. Chappell papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Church A. Chappell papers
1925-1953
74053
Hoover Institution Archives
2 manuscript boxes, 2 envelopes, 1 oversize folder (0.6 linear feet)
Diary, correspondence, orders, booklets, photographs, and printed matter, relating to American naval activities in the Philippines, 1935-1937, and at Pearl Harbor, 1941, and to the United States Naval Academy Postgraduate School.
Chappell, Church A., d. 1976.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1974.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
Captain, United States Navy
Scope and Content of Collection
Diary, correspondence, orders, booklets, photographs, and printed matter, relating to American naval activities in the Philippines, 1935-1937, and at Pearl Harbor, 1941, and to the United States Naval Academy Postgraduate School.
United States Naval Academy.; United States. Navy Officers.; Pearl Harbor (Hawaii), Attack on, 1941.; United States--Armed Forces--Philippines.; World War, 1939-1945--Naval operations.
- Writings and notes, undated (Box-folder 1: 1)
- Orders, 1925-1926 (Box-folder 1: 2)
- Printed matter on the U.S. Navy, 1925-1936 (Box-folder 1: 3)
- United States Naval Academy Postgraduate School materials, 1928-1930 (Box-folder 1: 4)
- Philippines correspondence, 1935-1937 (Box-folder 1: 5)
- Philippines printed matter, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 1: 6)
- Newspaper clippings, 1937-1945 (Box-folder 1: 7)
- Printed matter on the U.S. Navy and New Orleans, circa 1940-1945 (Box-folder 1: 8)
- War diary, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 1: 9)
- Herman Wouk poem, 1942 (Box-folder 1: 10)
- United States Naval Academy Postgraduate School materials, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 2: 1)
- Orders, 1942-1946 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes July 1942 change of duty orders for Commander Chappell that were declassified and released by Hoover in May 2015.
- Travel documents and miscellany, 1942-1946 (Box-folder 2: 3)
- Correspondence, 1944-1947 (Box-folder 2: 4)
- Guam materials, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 2: 5)
- Photographs, circa 1930s-1950s
  - Guam, 1950s (Photo file A)
    Includes photos of Chappell on duty in Guam, as well as a few photos of other officers and life on the base.
  - Ships and United States Naval Academy Postgraduate School, 1936, 1940s, 1952 (Photo file B)
    Includes three declassified photos from 5 April 1952 of the U.S.S. Wisconsin entering and being raised in the Auxiliary Dry Dock, Apra Harbor, Guam that were released by Hoover in May 2015. Additionally, there are two other photos of the U.S.S. Wisconsin, one of the U.S.S. Concord (1936), and a photo of a plane, possibly taken from the deck of the U.S.S. Salt Lake City (1942). There are also two photographs of Chappell during his tenure as Executive Officer of the United States Naval Academy Postgraduate School.
- Oversize file: Hawaii tourist map, 1930s and Philippines charts, 1937 (Oversize folder, Map case)